## Dinesh Jeyabalan

44 Jalan Serindik, Taman Ipoh, Ipoh, Perak. 31400







## **Objective**

To mold a successful character requires discipline and consistency in the delivery of one's responsibility irrelevant to the social and corporate challenges that arise during the process of performance. I seek to be that character.

### Summary

A licensed physiotherapist well-versed in a broad range of programming, treatments and therapeutic modalities to restore function and mitigating disabilities. Also, adequate in therapeutic intervention skills with 2 years of experience in both Healthcare and Fitness industry.

## **Experience**

#### Sport Therapist, True Yoga True Fitness, Singapore

Novena, Central — 2016 - 2017

Sports therapists work with sport and exercise participants to help prevent injuries, recognise, manage and treat them should they occur, and then rehabilitate the participant back to full fitness. Using the principles of sport and exercise science, sport therapist incorporate physiological and pathological processes to make sure participants are training and competing safely and provide an immediate response when sport and exercise related injuries occur.

#### Responsibility

- Examining and assessing injuries and determining whether the athlete or participant can continue safely with the event
- Mentally and physically preparing players, athletes and participants before a competition and using taping and massage techniques where necessary
- Conducting an assessment of the fitness level of players, athletes or participants and advising on exercises prior to an event or fixture;
- Testing joints for ease and range of movement, pain and dysfunction;
- Designing and monitoring rehabilitation programmes appropriate to the injury and/or sport and level

#### Junior Physiotherapy, REH-MEDIQ Szpital, Poland

Tyczyn, Rzeszow, Poland — 2014 - 2016

A physiotherapists involve helping people affected with injury, illness or disability through movement and exercise, manual therapy, education and advice. Maintain health for people of all ages, helping patients to manage pain and prevent disease. In my role in this profession, help to encourage, development and facilitate recovery, enabling people to stay in work while helping them to remain independent for as long as possible.

#### Responsibility

- Treating Pediatric condition especially with Weronika Sherborn technique,
   Bobath and Vojta methods.
- Physiotherapy intervention for Huntington disease.
- Gait re-education in Stance Phase and Swing Phase using traditional and modern based intervention
- Physiotherapy treatment for Bell's palsy
- Physiotherapy management for Ankylosing spondylitis.
- Musculoskeletal conditions Physiotherapy management for patients after fractures [Greenstick, Spiral, Compound, Linear and Traverse), crutch walking (2/ 3/ 4 point gait pattern or stair climbing training).
- Improve my treatment skills in treating Paediatric condition, especially engaging with Weronika Sherborn and Vojta methods.

#### **Exercise Specialist [Elite], Fitness First, Malaysia**

Fitness First Malaysia Team — 2012 - 2014

Exercise physiology role demands how the body reacts to physical exercise, in both the long and short term, and how the body adapts to ongoing exercise and any changes to a routine.

#### Responsibility

- Develop, design and implemented specific exercise programs and diet layouts based on targeting specific members with specific conditions such as obesity, high cholesterol, hypertension and arthritis.
- Personally interviewed members on a one to one basis to determine their personal fitness, injury management and health goals and demonstrate proper exercises for stretching, strengthening, endurance training, pelvic floor strengthening, aerobic and anaerobic.
- Motivate and encourage member to meet their fitness goals.

#### **Education**

#### Dr Claire McLean, Singapore

Exercise as Medicine for Individuals with Parkinson Disease - 2017

Dr. McLean is a Board Certified Neurologic Clinical Specialist. She graduated with a doctorate in physical therapy from the University of Southern California and has specialty training through the University of Southern California/Rancho Los Amigos Neurologic Physical Therapy Residency program. Her research on the benefits of exercise for individuals with Parkinson disease demonstrates significant improvements for many different aspects of health. For individuals to experience these benefits though, exercise needs to implemented as medicine. This requires attention to the type of exercise, dosage, and intensity among other variables. In her lecture we discuss the latest research and the implementation exercise as medicine.

#### Osteon Manual Therapy, Singapore

Advanced Dry Needling Certificate - 2017

Dry needling is an effective and efficient technique for the treatment of muscular pain and myofascial dysfunction. Dry needling or intramuscular stimulation (IMS) is a technique extremely effective for relaxing overactive muscles, which contain trigger points. The workshop was conducted by Giles (osteopath) and Jimmy (osteopath & exercise Physiologist), their approach based on Western anatomical and neurophysiological principles.

#### University of Information Technology and Management, Poland

Bachelor of Science in Physiotherapy - 2016

Thesis Topic : Assessment of Manipulative Therapy in Nonspecific Spine Pain

During my study period in this course I had the opportunity to learn about western based treatment that focus and emphasize on research based treatment. Another major obstacle was overcoming the essences of local dialects with learning the polish language with online program, group classes and among the local folks.

#### **Kinesio Taping International Association, London**

**Professional Certificate in Taping Technique-2016** 

Attending this workshop which was taught by Sabrina Arnulf, osteopathic and a physiotherapist. This workshop proved to be very resourceful and brought so much insight towards in treating dysfunction and reducing disabilities. The kinesio tape design to facilitate the body's natural healing process while providing support and stability to the muscle and joints without restricting the body's range of motion.

#### International Proprioceptive Neuromuscular Facilitation Association

Certificate in PNF Level 1 and 2 - 2015

This program gave me a solid understanding on how to use diagonal pattern in different position such as in Standing, Sitting, Crook lying, Quadruped and forth on.

I learn to use the diagonal 1 and 2 pattern for the upper, lower extremity, scapula and pelvic region to regress, maintain and progress. In addition to it I had also learned the PNF technique in approaching mat activities and gait training. The proposed mechanisms underlying the PNF response tends to involve 2 major factor that is autogenic inhibition and reciprocal inhibition.

#### International Young Scientific Student Conference, Poland

Participate on 2nd International Student Conference - 2015

Presented the Topic about Gait Mechanism and the distinct differences between ordinary and runner's gait. A controversy among two major giants that was Lionel Messi and Cristiano Ronaldo gait.

#### Fitness First WorkShop, Asia Team

Professional Workshop Series — 2012-2014

Fitness First training systems and methodologies represent the "gold standard" in fitness based on current scientific research. The workshop consist of basics of anatomy, physiology, kinesiology, nutrition, behavioral coaching, and how to design a program specific to our clients' needs and abilities to help them achieve their goals safely and effectively.

#### Mahsa University, Malaysia

Diploma in Physiotherapy — 2009-2012

MAHSA University had generate a pool of skilled healthcare professionals including myself. MAHSA was established in earnest in the year 2005 with the belief that higher education in the field of healthcare. MAHSA had taught me the basic key elements of healthcare career especially in a physiotherapist profession.

#### **Methodist Anglo Chinese School**

Primary & Secondary Education — 1997 - 2008

Completed the primary school evaluation test and Malaysian Certificate of Education in the same school. English test are monitored on Cambridge level examiners as stated on the back of each result held.

#### **Skills**

- Good interpersonal skills
- Proficient in various pain management settings
- Good verbal communication skills
- Specialization in neurological conditions
- Good non-verbal communication skills
- Passionate in manipulative therapy techniques.
- Enthusiastic, gentle and skillful in therapeutic procedures.
- Conduct workshops

## Inspiration

My passion in the field of physiotherapy started from a young age growing up with my mother who was also involved in the medical field as a staff nurse. She was my inspiration all along. My desire is to equip myself with the latest state of the art knowledge/research in this particular field. This can only be achieved by working with the best in a renowned medical organisations.

#### A. MEDICAL FIELD REFERENCES

#### References

1. Professor and Chairman MIROSLAW BOGDAN JABLONSKI Physician, Consultant in Orthopaedics and Rehabilitation Chair and Department of Rehabilitation and Orthopaedics of Lublin Medical University
20-094 Lublin, ul. K. Jaczewskiego 8 (University Hospital no 4 in Lublin, Poland)
+48 81 7244184
mbjablonski@gmail.com

#### 2. SABRINA ARNULF

Master in Osteopathic Medicine, Certified Lymphoedema Therapist CLT at GeeCol Lymphoedema Service, Kinesio taping Instructor at Kinesio UK Nowton court heritage wellbeing centre, Bury St. Edmunds IP29 5LU / Suffolk, United Kingdom 07534457394 s.arnulf@outlook.com

#### 3. WERNER WIMMEROTH

PNF Advance Senior Instructor, Maitland and Bobath Instructor, N.A.P assistant therapist
Am Saynschen Hof 8 D53604 Bad Honnef, Germany
00492224 10650
Info@zehn650.de

# 4. DOMINIK PIKULA Doctor of Physiotherapy Hospital Rudna Mala Szpital Specjalistyczny 36-060 Rudna Mała, Rzeszów, Poland +48-784-010-420 dominpiku@gmail.com

5. MICHEAL Head of Physiotherapy Department of REH-MEDIQ Orkana Nr.6, Tyczyn, Rzeszów, Poland +48-667372666 idzikowski82@gmail.com

#### **B. CHARACTER REFERENCES**

#### 1. MUHENDRAN

Fitness First General Manager Concourse Level, Menara Axis, No.2 Jln 51A/223, 46100 Petaling Jaya, Selangor. +60-129-106-823 Skyline.muhen93@gmail.com

#### 2. MACIEJ KOCHMAN

Doctor of Physiotherapy Dean Associate [Faculty of Medicine, UITM]] UI. Sucharskiego 2, 35-225 Rzeszów, Poland +48-888-500-541

Maciejkochman@hotmail.com

#### 3. SAW YEW WENG

Financial Market Operation Manager, Scope International Division, Standard Chartered Damansara Utama, Petaling Jaya, 47400 Selangor +6016 212 8620 yweng87@gmail.com